# JASON DELIA

# FRONT END SOFTWARE ENGINEER WITH MBA

# **BIO**

Experienced front end software engineer with MBA. Builds usercentric solutions to deliver bestin-class web applications.

### **SKILLS**

 $\mathsf{HTML} \cdot \mathsf{CSS} \cdot \mathsf{JS} \cdot \mathsf{Responsive}$ design · React · Git · Grunt · CSS Preprocessors · Iterative design process · Adobe Creative Suite · Strategy · User research · Management

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **MBA**

New York Institute of Technology

# **BS**, Business Administration

Seton Hall University

#### CONTACT



jasonadelia@gmail.com



631.949.5979



@jasonadelia



jasondelia.com



/jasonadelia



/jasonadelia

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# **Staff Software Engineer - UI**

MediaMath 2017 - Present

Provide technical direction for the UI engineering organization.

- Assume ownership of the code base and ensure all changes meet our quality standards
- Lead the technical architecture and delivery of complex projects
- Provide mentoring opportunities for junior engineers
- Collaborate with product, design, and other stakeholders across the organization

# **Senior Product Designer**

Nasdag 2013 - 2016

Serve as the product design team's technical director.

- Lead the creation of style guides and a pattern library for teams across the organization
- Establish coding standards, guidelines and develop frameworks to enable rapid prototyping
- Participate in user research, discovery interviews, and usability testing
- Design and develop high fidelity prototypes using HTML, CSS and IS
- Interaction work patented by Nasdaq (US D764,543)

# Senior Web Developer

Thomson Reuters 2005 - 2013

Build and maintain Thomson Reuters' Investor Relations hosting platform. Responsible for front end development using ASP.NET, HTML, JS, and CSS.

- Develop reusable front end components that power investor relations websites for Fortune 500 companies
- Contribute to middle tier and database development
- Write and unit test code for new products and bug fixes
- Write and review technical specifications

# **Website Developer**

Thomson Financial 2002 - 2005

Work closely with product managers to build investor relations websites for clients.

- Develop and document well-designed and easily maintainable websites using HTML, JS, CSS and other web technologies
- Provide support and knowledge sharing with other site building teams and account managers

# **COMMUNITY**

Councilman, Borough of Metuchen, 2019 - Present

Founder & Mentor, CoderDojo Metuchen, 2015 - Present

Head of Communications & Street Smart NJ Project Lead, Metuchen Traffic and Transportation Advisory Committee, 2015 - Present

Web Designer & Developer, Metuchen Farmers Market, 2014 - Present

Speaker, Nasdaq // Fullstaq, NYC UXPA, February 2016

**Speaker**, Designing with Web Components, Pro/Design, January 2015